[Music]
welcome to embedded I am Alesia white
and my co-host is Christopher white our
guest this week is Axl Parchman we'll be
talking about security and embedded
systems there are some things I think
you should know before we get started
with Axl I have a 40% off coupon or
three to the particle spectra conference
in October in San Francisco hit the
contact link on embedded fm if you want
one and if you really want one really
compliant to attend and are out of a job
or in school and a random number in case
I have a free to get to give away as
well Axl thanks for joining us hi let's
see hi Chris could you tell us about
yourself sure I'm currently responsible
for the harbor security lab at Dark
Matter but at heart I'm a curious
engineer was a passion for efficiency I
did my PhD on lightweight crypto was
Chris of power in Bochum Germany and
then did my postdoc at NTU in Singapore
where eventually became an assistant
professor and build up my own research
group then my research focus shifted
towards implementation security so that
has in particular efficient
countermeasures against such an old Ford
attacks for embedded devices then around
five years ago I pivoted it to industry
and started at NXP Semiconductors in
Hamburg Germany since my curiosity
wanted to get completely new inputs and
then again around one and a half years
ago I moved to Abu Dhabi in the United
Arab Emirates again out of curiosity and
Here I am building up our security law
all right what's the height oh wait a
minute I have to introduce lightning
rounds before I just start going to it
don't know so we'll ask you short
questions we want you to have short
answers it'll be a little silly I bet
and then we will get into the meat of
embedded security safest form of
computer stay away from it
do you prefer to start a dozen projects
or finish one actually both - I want to
start a dozen and then get satisfaction
when one offer the other completes worst
movie for depicting hacking possible
saltfish okay yeah passwords sorts I
think it's called fresh hair but I do
standards make things safer or easier to
hack do my what standards are standards
yeah that make things safer hacking
making tinkering engineering or
programming engineering it's hacking a
good thing or a bad thing it's good
because it creates pressure to improve
product security alright one more
what's the tip you think everyone should
know it's the indicator at the guest
tank it shows you which side of the car
your guests hangar opens it took me a
long time before I realized that there's
a little little indicator like when you
have a fuel gauge yeah there's a little
carrot on the signage it says which side
the the door is on yeah I didn't know
that until like five years ago you do
that forever
of course yeah ok so you you have a PhD
and you do security and
I get so intimidated by security it just
seems like an impossible problem is
anything you can tell me that will keep
me from being just overwhelmed and
futility sure so I think there's no
right you can't do security completely
right from my point of view it's just a
trade-off so security is another
dimension that runs contrary to use
abilities performance time-to-market
cost and all the other engineering
trade-offs and wherever your customer is
you want to be comfortable and and
reducing the other optimization goals
that's where you'll end where's your
security and and if it's never perfect
you can never make it completely secure
well that's the show thank you
everywhere I did I've done a very small
amount of security work kind of fell out
of being a firmware engineer at one
place and then I kind of fell into this
one role there and that was really
striking to me the the management really
wanted it to be perfect and I kept
telling them this is the best we can do
and it's always going to be a little bit
of cat and mouse how would you present
or convince people who really aren't
familiar with security and do think it
can be perfect that there is it good
enough well that's in the end it boils
down to risk management I think if you
can show in particular management that
you know the risk you can quantify it as
best as possible and you have done all
your homeworks like following best
practices security guidelines standards
and so on then there should be a point
where people accept the risk and move
forward otherwise you will never hit the
market or the cost will explode or
usability goes to zero how do I tell my
clients are my managers are my
that it is worth spending the time and
money on security when all they want to
do is ship my consumer product yes I
think it's the core of the challenge I
would say yeah I think it's the
challenge boards don't actually to a
lack of measurement for security
security is multi-dimensional so and
everybody has a different understanding
of what security actually is so even if
there are metrics to measure it it's
very hard to quantify it and to show
improvement you'll need to first agree
on a metric and then measure and then
show that you have improved and that the
time has been worth spent on improving
the security because in the end for
product development time and money is
easy to measure you either hit the
deadlines or not you either hit the cost
or not so these are kind of binary
decisions where security is everything
between zero and one and the value to
the end customer really depends on
someone else often like did this device
get hacked and go into the script Kitty
denial-of-service system or did my
system just wasn't that interesting so
nobody hacked it and so how much I spend
on security should be reflected in that
or should be proportional to how much
it's attacked but I have no control over
one of those correct and and also I
think security is valuable if you don't
see it only if something is breached you
know it wasn't secured until it wasn't
an act or breached you can't say for
sure it's secure just because no one has
found a way to hack it
or hasn't published it so I think that's
also one way to convince maybe
management to invest the time is to make
it slightly better than come
because burglars always go for the
lowest hanging fruits and that's the
same for a cross if they see this one
your product is harder to hack then they
may go to a competitor product instead
forget the same financial benefits yeah
you don't have to be faster than the
bear you just have to be faster than the
other person yes
so you mentioned some standards
what can I look at what can I point to
to say this this is good advice
this is cogent advice yeah I think this
depends on your target application or
your product so sometimes there are
regulatory requirements I think the NIST
is doing a great job in publishing
guidelines there is for for tamper
protection which can be the first
boundary or first protection level
against attackers they're very good
implementation guidelines how to achieve
a certain level of tamper protection
there are firmware security guidelines
and best practices for coding and and
design everywhere available just a quick
google search there plenty of advice
available for designers there is but
there's so much and I wish there was
more specifically rated related to
embedded systems without operating
systems or without Linux I mean we've
talked about the cert top ten secure
coding practices but most of those are
things you do when you have a Linux
system if there
is there a book or a site you trust so
I've never designed the secure product I
was only part of it typically in the red
team capacity so I never really made an
exhaustive literature survey what is
available there are few good references
so for example my PhD advisor has a
complete lecture series available at
YouTube so that that's a very good start
obviously it's 24 hours of YouTube
videos so that's maybe too much time to
to invest but there are also other
guidelines that from the anisa which is
a European organization they published a
guideline in particular for embedded
devices and how to how to harden the
platform and to mitigate some threats
that embedded devices face that one had
some interesting tables where a lot of
times when I talk to clients they think
about one aspect they think maybe about
their user passwords or maybe they think
about having their firmware ease dropped
upon that a hardware threat landscape
and good practice guide had some tables
that listed all kinds of things and the
effects from nefarious activity and how
that affects information integrity to
actual damage and whether that makes it
available or causes environmental harm
to evil even legal problems that come up
when people steal your software and that
laying out the threats like that was
very helpful to me because it's it's
nice to not have to reinvent it each
time
so being on the red team and just just
to make sure the red team are the is the
penetration team they're they're the
hackers and the blue team is usually the
defenders who build the thing is that
that that's the right terminology yeah
correct how do you if I bring you
something
I bring you Oh an internet of things
light and it hooks up over Wi-Fi which
not the best option but still what do
you do first do you take it apart do you
look at the software what what do you do
all right so all right I'm working about
will app and we have a software lab
telecommunications lab and a mile war
lab so whenever we get a device and in
our lab then the team starts
simultaneously to work on it and we
focus on the hardware offered advice so
we have a look at it if there are any
debug interface is available that's the
first easy to check access point if
there's a JTAG enabled you can do a lot
of things the second thing is if you
open up the device you check the printed
circuit board and try to identify the
components and try to reverse-engineer
all the components that have been built
in there then you check CVEs
that are associated to those components
and try if their vulnerabilities have
been closed in that design or not then
you try to dump the firmware or you
never look at the PCB if you can find
some x pins have been disconnected in
order to make the debug interface is not
accessible you can just sort of the pins
on it and voila you have your debug
interfaces and I can do stuff and if all
that doesn't work you can go on the chip
level you can take off the secure memory
or CPU or whatever and put it in a but
probably not worth for an IT light
device but you can then do physical
attacks like such an attacks or fault
attacks you can try to glitch the boot
process to to boot the devil and another
boot image which even gives you good
access so you can dump the memory or you
can do such an analysis trying to get
the cryptographic keys out of it yeah so
that plenty of things you can do you
said sidechain analysis
yeah when I say site Shannon okay site
channel yeah so I'm talking for me such
an in particular means power aside
channels or electromagnetic side
channels but obviously it's in spectrum
out on cash timing attacks way way more
important side channels so that's the
sort of thing like that the chip
whisperer that yeah where you monitor it
power exactly and you can figure out the
cryptographic keys based on how the
power is done when it decrypts it I
remember hearing about that and thinking
wow that's bonkers and amazing and
terrifying which is kind of where I am
right now okay so if I'm on the blue
team not having JTAG as an easy-access
although that makes manufacturing it's
so much harder yeah and making sure my
debug pins
certainly aren't labeled debug and have
a header would stop you just a little
bit but I need those D big pins they're
at different manufacturing ah and then
you can take out my firmware by
decapping the chip but decapping the
chip is more expensive than just reading
it out through JTAG yeah but only
slightly so they're companies we can
just send the chips that you kept it for
you you can use kind of specialized
chemistry but it's still freely
available and into it yourself in the
garage that doesn't
of YouTube videos showing you how to do
it it's just a little bit of time and
effort that you need to invest and it
was just a little bit of practice every
gradient student can can do it
so a decapping a chip is this is not a
big girl okay I feel like the red team
won yeah well there's a good question so
are there things that you come across
that and you have to say what they are
but that do you just okay we can't we've
figured nothing out or is it basically
everything is penetrable once you have
hardware in hand yeah I would say
everything is penetrable but it's the
question is if the effort is worth yeah
the the price and there is for our
security this is common criteria and the
J has subgroup joint Harper assurance
security I think it's a meaning of
juniors they have rating tables for
specific products so if you talk about a
smart card or a secure device with
security boxes and their different
dimensions or factors that all give
points like the two words that you use
is it a chip Whisperer $450 or do you
need a $50,000 high-end oscilloscope or
a focused ion beam for million dollars
or a laser for the injection device for
$100,000 so you get different points for
the price on the availability of the
tools for the duration of the tech that
it takes to do it for the knowledge that
you need for the number of samples and a
few other dimensions and then there's an
exploitation phase and an identification
phase and for each of them you add the
points together and if you get more than
31 points then you get the highest
assurance for this device and that
doesn't mean that a nation state
couldn't break it sure how I'm motivated
taker but it clearly is the highest
grade that you can get in that you can
certify so I think this is a better
approach you can hack everything you try
to quantify the multi-dimensional effort
that an attacker has to put in and try
to come up with was a rating okay so so
there's this rating and I can basically
get a score and I can probably work out
how much each point costs I mean they
aren't all going to be the same but if
if my boss wants to get a better score I
can say well each point costs about
three people weeks of work I say that
without having any knowledge of how long
it actually takes and then it's probably
somewhat exponential at the beginning
you it's easier to lock your JTAG than
it is to redesign your platform so
you'll have a chip that has reasonably
protected does that all sound about
right I mean is this the story I'm
telling myself is about right yeah I
mean there's again the many dimensions
and in one example what you mentioned is
correct
the engineering effort and designing
more counter measures can translate to
points but this is just one dimension
for example knowledge of the device is
another very important dimension and
that's also the reason why smart cards
don't provide a lot of very detailed
technical manuals to everybody but only
to vetted customers because the
availability of this information would
cost points and the evaluation and
people always complain about this and
say this is QE bomb obscurity but in
fact it's it's a mechanism to make it
harder to attack the device and coming
back to this example if you want to
really fulfill all the requirements to
keeping this information tightly secured
it means you need to have a high
and secure IT environment you need
parameter security with at least two or
three different zones so that means two
or three different checkpoints and
gantries where you need to go from one
to a point from one zone to the other so
there are a lot of lot of extra costs
that translate into these points yes we
were talking recently about a consumer
product where the question was I'm
shipping a lot of these and how do I
make them secure enough not to be
laughed at and we talked some about in
manufacturing making passwords different
and forcing users to change password
upon receipt of the device but it was
Chris you brought up this doesn't matter
if your database if your server device
is unprotected you have to protect the
whole chain when you say zones what do
you mean by that so the physical zones
like you have a fence around your
factory office and then and then you
have another country where you need to
batch in and there's no tailgating
allowed there's a security guard
watching it or CCTV in operation and
from that zone you can enter vendor
high-security zone and then if a similar
separation in your IT network so the
high secure network which is no internet
access kind of a DMZ and then a kind of
company-wide
intranet okay I'm glad I asked because I
had this idea that it was areas on a
board people do get a notion that it's
all about the device right oh if you can
hack the device I'm doomed and then they
do some strange back-end that is not
security well then it's not just
attacking the device there's lots of
ways to attack the ecosystem of your
product right yeah correct yeah yeah
well I was stressing only this this
whole overhead it only translates to a
few points in a device evaluation
because it means you have the
appropriate measure someplace to protect
the data sheets and the hardware designs
of your product if you don't have this
in place you don't get the points
because that he could be hacked and then
the data is out something else I've
never thought about I am always in favor
of publicly available data sheets and
manuals because as an engineer that
makes my life so much easier and when I
have to sign an NDA to see a chip manual
it's irritating if there was a reason
for it
yeah I think obviously the functionality
should be still publicly available but
the detailed working of the
countermeasures needs to be closely
guarded you worked in an XP in their
hardware security area yes can you tell
me more about what you did there yeah so
for the first two years I was running
the one ability analysis team and that's
such an ax
fault attacks and invasive Hardware
attacks and there was an internal red
team that hacked from hardware
perspective all the high-end security
chips that NXP produced the situations
and became in at several stages of the
design cycle from simulations to
prototypes to pre variation risk
mitigation and obviously always gave
feedback to the designers how to improve
things and what was easy to hack what is
a it's a pain and in general how to
improve the product so that's what I did
for the first two years and then for the
last year I was responsible for the
security concepts team which was also
for the high-end hardware security
practice with a Linux P and trying to
I don't notice a it's trying to steal
the innovation and the creativity of
this great team towards products so that
all these ideas and patents that have
been filed and papers that have been
published eventually ended up in
products of an XP high security chips
are there things in the hardware that
make firmware more secure yeah I think
fuses I would example like when I set
the JTAG fuse so that you can't read out
my firmware or you can't use the attack
yes so that that's the simple measure
which just makes life a lot harder for
an attacker it's not impossible to
overcome it but I would say it it
probably keeps a majority of attackers
out because now they have to do
something like decapping which means
buying a few of my limits okay
yeah or even more so I think to reverse
the fuse you really need to change the
ICS we need to circuit editing which
means you need to use a flip which means
you need to go and render Thep which
cost a few thousand dollars and you have
the knowledge and you need to know where
to do what you fuse to change in all
these things so this is quite or much
more sophisticated than just decapping
and having a look at it or or just
dumping your firmware okay well what's a
tip it's a focused ion beam okay so it's
a failure analysis tool which can be
used for circuit editing why wouldn't I
just decap the chip read out the flash
flash it to another chip and call it
good well the Teredo the memory to
private reading out the memory that the
fuse has been burnt Rhino has been blown
oh so you just change the state of the
shoes when you decrypt the chip you just
get the bare silicon out because the
Raman
masker on me out but not not something
like not the flash drum I don't think
you can see any physical with flash huh
all right I learned something new all
the time that I thought I knew could be
girls
I don't think so though okay okay so you
have to change it so you can actually
read it out and then when you're reading
it out you're reading out through like a
JTAG interface not through microscopic
interface yeah exactly I mean that's
another way to try to use other Fae
analysis techniques to try to read out
the EEPROM on the flash but that's much
more sophisticated so it's much easier
to just try to reverse a state of a
protection fuse and then use the normal
mechanisms to read out the memory what
are their chip level tools exist for
firmware security that's a good question
so actually I'm in commercial devices
I'm only aware of fuses which use a lot
of products and secure elements there's
a complete different architecture there
are situations of passive devices so
it's a complete different architecture
than the moma CPU or an APU so I would
say fuses is cars set of the odd that's
kind of sad but nice to know that I do
know what the state of the art is and
and it's a little hard on embedded
systems because you can't track
intrusion very easily and so when you do
get hacked there's no way to tell
anybody on Linux systems that's part of
that's part of good security is being
able to tell when an intrusion has
occurred are there other things like
that where little devices and larger
devices have very different approaches
well that's I mean no move on
I don't know I think it's a tricky
question there's so many different
classes of smaller and embedded devices
and for example if you look at secure
elements again so the chips aren't smart
cards or passports on credit cards so
the highest grade hardware security
chips they have a lot of intrusion
detection and temper mechanisms but most
of them are passive so because the
device is passive so once it's powered
up then they erase the keys or erasing
memory these kind of things but it's not
that an alarm is sent to some remote
operator it all happens in that chip so
but again this is for secure element and
not for the standard IOT chip yeah I
worked on a a sensor that in military
use you could push a button and it would
erase its Hardware multi-race it's code
multiple times and all of its keys until
it ran out of batteries that's sort of
slagging the hardware was expensive but
if you really don't want somebody to
have it that's what you do you sometimes
talk about open source when you're doing
conference presentations do you have
opinions about whether open source is
really useful or is it only useful in
certain cases so I think open sources is
great it has done it's impossible to to
clearly state what benefits open source
has done to innovation and security and
humanity in general I think it's a bit
tricky for hardware because you can't
just push in an update so if that was in
the field you can't change it there's
only a few things that you can change
was firmware updates but some flaws you
cannot fix
other than changing the artwork and I
think that's where also the reluctance
from the vendors come in to publish
details about their designs
and if you look at spectrum art on it
haunts the chip industry no because no
one has checked it for four decades but
if you combine that with a mandatory
third-party testing approach like what
is done for certified secure element for
example then it can work you just need
to make sure that a lot of people have a
look at your design with different ideas
how to hack it and you take that
feedback and improve on it and then
that's the beauty of open source once
it's out everybody can ever look at it
and try to find a loophole and and soon
enough all these dew points are closed
or a lot of people know about these
loopholes and they're not telling anyone
well it's run contrary to the to the
notion of securing your infrastructure
and your designs and things if that's
true why not open everything up well I
think it's very beneficial to keep a lot
of things secret because it adds
additional pain for the attacker if you
can't get the design principle if you
can't get the countermeasures if you
can't get all the tripwires that you put
in place it's really a pain and at some
point hopefully they lose patience and
move on to the next target that's why I
think in order to increase product
security it's very beneficial to keep
these details
closely guarded but then again it needs
to be make sure that independent red
teams have had a look at this design to
not make any beginners mistakes and so
there's this dichotomy if you want to
keep the information I need to know
because then people who don't need to
know don't have it and can't misuse it
but having open sore
gives you more eyes and more security
for everyone in general and they seem
like opposite paths it's true okay I
mean if if you look at the state of
software security Oh
IOT security most of the device devices
use open source libraries in one way or
the other or modified it or don't tell
people that they use open source
libraries and still there's a lot of
insecurity around it so I think open
source and and the power of crowd
intelligence having look at these
software things improve the best
achievable state of security but what is
then implemented in the average product
it's a completely different story I mean
one of the good things about open source
security libraries is that you're not
implementing your own fantastical
made-up algorithm that may have a
shortcut I have haven't gotten past that
point where everybody's implementing
their own security are we on to the next
problem now or do you still see a lot of
people saying well I just have 2 modulo
and add and then multiply by 3 and then
the number is always 12 when you get it
back okay I'm I think open-source
libraries is great because you have
exactly as I said you have proven secure
implementations or at least a vast pool
of volunteers hasn't found any flaws in
these libraries so you have a very good
security level already for software I
think for Hardware you don't have all
these building blocks readily available
if for crypto you shouldn't change
anything and the block ciphers the hash
functions public key crypto all this is
secure and secure since decades so
there's no need to implement anything by
yourself
when I say it's beneficial to closely
guard what you uses then you have to use
proven principles
that are known to be secure but maybe
add some extra layers of obfuscation or
extra the obfuscation pretty much on top
to make life hard but again it needs to
be checked that this is no influence on
the underlying security principles
people make fun of obfuscation as a
security measure so it's a little odd to
hear you say it can you explain more
about okay maybe what's a good example
yeah yeah when you look at a chip and
you can clearly identify all the
building blocks and it's easy to go for
the key storage or the fuses of a CPU or
the registers if you use glue logic
which is kind of an obfuscated Hardware
layout it's very hard to find it
and makes life one attacker really
really painful okay and you you could
give an infinite time as a hacker
unravel the glue logic but it would be
much easier to just walk in and it the
key is there and easy to find yeah I
mean this is example from Kristen or
Sookie hacking a SKU element form
Infineon finger was like six years ago
and he found the coprocessor and he
found a way to hack this coprocessor on
the secure core processor reusing this
design in other devices and other
derivatives of this product is good for
me economic point of view but it also
means that these other devices can be
egg was the same attack vector and if
they had been glue logic used just as an
example then it wouldn't be obvious
where these modules would have been and
by the attacker would have to go so
that's also why reverse engineering is
actually a very interesting research
topic because there no metrics how
difficult it is to
kind of reverse and obfuscation but
reverse engineering like hacking does
sometimes have a bad reputation how do
you how do you deal with that well I'm
not doing reverse engineering but I
admire people who do it because it's
very tedious work typically I'd need a
lot of knowledge and years of experience
to to be efficient in it I think
currently if you want to make your
product secure you need to add some
layers of obfuscation on top just to
make life painful and then not that
every script kiddie can go to youtube
tutorial and and employ some making
tricks on your product at the same time
it's unclear which your first occasion
is really effective and you mentioned
that people are laughing at obfuscation
this is typically because it's not very
effective okay going back to example
earlier with I want to make an Internet
of Things light I write some firmware
it's not Linux so it's not open to those
attack factors and what do i what are
the things that are the easiest cheapest
engineering things to do for the biggest
bang for the buck as far as making it
secure so that it doesn't just get
hacked in the first week it's out okay
you first should define your assets what
do you want to protect if it's a firm
where is it keys user data whatever once
you have the assets defined you can do a
threat modeling so see how these assets
could be compromised by adversaries and
which means the processor needs to do to
get to these assets and then you can
define your countermeasures and
low-hanging fruits are always to use
constant time implementation of crypto
or use standard crypto libraries that
have constant time implementations
then forth countermeasures can be built
in there's some coding guidelines and so
on like the cards the time is to avoid
the side-channel attacks yeah correct so
whenever you touch a key a crypto key
then there's a chance that this
information can be picked up through
side channels and time is easiest
typically computer scientist or engineer
want to optimize algorithms for the
average best performance but that means
it's data dependent so if you make it
data independent it's always the worst
case execution time which is secure but
it's also the worst case execution ever
every time but these are low-hanging
fruits so then you already have this
timing side shanna close out ok let's
let's see if I can figure out what the
assets are one of my assets is the
password and username that my user uses
on the server another might be the
user's Wi-Fi password because I need
that to log on to their Wi-Fi another
asset would be being able to see
remotely whether the light is on or off
which might indicate whether the person
is home or not and then another asset
did you say like pairing certification
certificate or something like that I
didn't but that's a good one a pairing
certificate so that I knew on the server
that this device belonged to me and
should be handled adequately those are
those are those the assets did I miss a
bunch is that sound about right give it
a spherical IOT light that sounds good
it sounds like it's challenged to secure
it without any Linux or any other
standards libraries available yeah
welcome to my world so let's talk about
that
difficut that I want to I want this
light to be able to talk to my server
and so when it leaves manufacturing it
gets her certificate that says yeah you
can talk to my server if I use the same
certificate for everybody then a hacker
can come in and make a fake light a
spoof light a clone yep
a clone yes okay and that that is a sort
of example of threat modeling where I go
through my list of assets and I think
about oh if I did this with it then
someone could do that with it
yeah I mean using this same certificate
in all devices probably I think IP
cameras or something yeah where they use
the same private RSA key in all devices
because someone who read the checklist
probably didn't get that it means you
need to be unique key that is completely
random and so on it's a force yeah I
mean it may try to generate a unique key
and have to program each device
individually instead of just mashing the
same Rama over and over again that's
hard I mean as a manufacturing step that
is a pain in the neck
yeah it's provisioning all right it's
key provisioning and it also needs to
happen in a secure facility to make sure
no one else can tempo is that key which
is yeah there's a lot of times that's
overseas right you're not necessarily in
control of that facility but
provisioning can also happen on premise
so you can you can do it separately from
the manufacturing yeah this is shipping
boards to the states and then shipping
them out from here yeah for domestic
here yeah that was a companies who offer
that as a service because the key needs
to be generated in a secure way right so
you need an HSM our security module to
generate the key and our edges
it's been a parameter secured
environment was excess control and so on
and so forth
so you're saying I shouldn't just plus
plus the previous number
what about use the serial number of the
the chip that I'm using well it's again
one of these trade-offs between costs
time to market usability and security
and performance if you have a like but
and the serial number is only available
to an attacker a fee this you know takes
out the light but from the from the lamp
and has to look at it then yeah probably
you can use it because that's he's
already in the premise and then gets the
serial number and that's part of threat
modeling to is identifying when okay the
threat already has whatever the threat
wants so we don't have to protect beyond
this point they're already they've
already broken the window and gotten in
the house they know whether or not the
humans home now we just have to protect
our server so that they can't do that to
everybody all right okay so wait what
was this step after throughout Marlene
okay so then you can derive the security
requirements for a product so if you
want to prevent certain attacks or you
can react to certain you can mitigate
attacks and in this case we just talked
about serial number you want to make
sure that it's not easily available
remotely for an adversary so I think
putting a sticker on there on the light
but somewhere where you need to be very
very close to the light Bob could
already be a good way but then I
shouldn't put it in my database on my
server and use that as a key to organize
my light bulbs because that means that
if somebody has my server they have the
keys to everything that's actually
shipped sure it goes in the key material
as one of the factors well there should
be other factors as well
yes and ideally those are partially
company-wide and partially device wide
and partially just unique to this device
yes but manufacturing constraints and
costs may limit what is unique okay so I
have decided I've modeled my threats I
have chosen some things that I'm going
to defend against I've implemented that
in ways that don't open me up to other
things in in ways that are accepted by
the industry and then I think the next
thing I need to do is the independent
third-party testing is that the usual
next step yeah I mean typically you
should have a rat team early on it
should be basically once you have a
threat modeling done and derived your
security requirements someone else just
check whether you have overseen
something because at this point of time
you can easily change your design
whereas if you don't do that and you
have a product you can't change the
hardware the architecture may be very
difficult or impossible to to fix any
flaws that you may have overlooked
so the rat team ideally an independent
third-party evaluator should come in
very early and then once the prototype
is there and your feedback of the
evaluator has been implemented there
should be a testing round and
potentially on the final product again
so that makes a lot of sense to me for
things that our infrastructure important
but it would be hard to sell for my
consumer IOT device hard to sell to the
people who make decisions about whether
to pay for it yeah because it would be
expensive I mean this is not good this
is not ever going to be a $500 test it's
not even gonna be an FCC multi-thousand
dollar test it's gonna be expensive to
get a proper third-party test of
curity because you have to dig into the
details of the system correct but there
are this is an ideal case if you aim for
highest security if you have a light but
and if you to the threat modeling
properly probably you don't need to have
the highest security standards for a
light bulb but what you can do is you
can employ you can collaborate with
universities or freelancers who have
credentials who have knowledge in that
fields and that's typically much much
cheaper than working with some proper
testing laboratory you obviously get
less but it's better than nothing and
it's much better than you're not doing
it at all yeah that's it that that was
I'm glad you said that that was what I
wanted was you to say if you can't if
you can't afford over the big bucks
because your team isn't big enough that
doesn't mean you just raise your hands
and say oh well well if we can't you
can't do third-party testing we just
won't do security that's that is not the
right answer what you should do is you
should just release your product and
then let people attack it find out
what's wrong recall it and then make the
correct one you could do that the brand
survives the damage so you just change
the brand name yeah yes sounds good
but I also think money is not
necessarily the biggest hurdle I think
it's time to market that really yeah
suffers or drive some most decisions and
and that's where security suffers
because typically we need a couple of
iterations to to get it right even if
your security professional even even at
XP we didn't get it first time right we
had a couple of test chips before we had
a real product because it's very very
hard to do it first time right it sounds
like much of engineering you are going
to be speaking at the hardware IO
conference in separate
Kember which is coming up really soon
can you tell me about the conference and
what you'll be speaking on yeah so
conference is a two-day conference
together with two days of trainings
that's a very practical hands-on focus
for both the training as well as the
conference topics are all areas of
harbour security and I've speaking about
different aspects of our security
so challenges for security zone in
general or for IT particular the lack of
incentives for secure design importance
of independent security testing pros and
cons of open source and the importance
of reverse engineering so a little bit
similar to what we discussed in this
podcast so basically we were helping you
write your talk okay yeah you said the
incentive to put the timelines of bits
earlier to bring in the timeline yeah
have you seen this may be something you
discussed because just listening to you
mentioned the incentives to to go do
some good design have you seen over time
that the more higher profile incidents
and attacks have led to people being
more responsible or or at least trying
to ask the right questions more often or
is it kind of still a free-for-all so I
think unfortunately the only the really
brand damaging hex and breaches and
publications really changed
industry-wide behavior and the more
damaging the publications of results
were the quicker industry reacted so I
think Charlie Miller and the g-pack even
though it's yes it's kind of interesting
to reveal all these vulnerabilities
which cannot be fixed before industry
can fix it
I think that has changed automotive
security for the goods dramatically and
this was when he actually Charlie was a
journalist and he invited someone to
take over his Jeep correct and then he
was a little shocked and appalled at
their driving quietly about the streets
yeah I mean I think this really made
headlines everybody heard about it it
has nice pictures had a nice story
and suddenly in automotive people who
are willing to invest money to for
security
even though cars are very expensive it's
actually very very cost driven industry
and if you if you increase the price for
a few cents
people will heck are you down and give
you a hard time and what I heard here is
that for so now I am from Germany they
were willing to increase the spending
for security fivefold just after this
egg oh the way from a nickel to a
quarter but that's it's good that it's
talked about because automotive is an
industry that tends to move very slow
and if we can do better there then other
industries will maybe be a little bit
more aware that we can't just keep
hoping that somebody else's products are
attacked and that ours are given a free
pass that's not gonna last forever
well axle do you have any thoughts you
would like to leave us with well I'd
like to thank you for being on your show
I also like to mention that I'm still
looking for a few talented people who
are willing to work in our security so
that would be a good opportunity to
reach out to me what are you looking for
embedded firmware but it's hard
Engineers or or security researchers yes
so I'm looking for security researcher
for our secure researcher and but it's
secured researchers and we have
cutting-edge lab and interesting
everyday challenges as projects where we
need to do security assessments and it's
a very international team the lab is
based in Abu Dhabi United Arab Emirates
is it I guess I shouldn't say is it as
beautiful there as I think because how
would you know what I think so actually
is very beautiful because the offices
are right next to the rebbe engulfed
so there's turquoise border surrounding
the office the other day we saw a shark
swimming by so it's pretty nice yeah and
how should they contact you they can
always email on the show if they want
and I will make introductions but if
they want to contact you directly is
there a good way to do that yeah it's
probably best to just connect with me on
LinkedIn and send a message okay okay
our guest has been axel parchment head
of the hardware lab at dark matter LLC
is the closings keynote at the hardware
IO conference in The Hague in
mid-september axel thank you for being
with us thanks for having me thank you
also to the folks at hardware Toyo for
connecting me to axel thank you to
patreon supporters for Axel's microphone
thank you to particle i/o for their
conference coupons and giveaway don't
forget about those you have until
September 15th to email me for them
numerous links will be in the show notes
if you want to know more and you can
check them out on your podcast app or on
embedded fm on the web thank you to
Christopher for producing and co-hosting
and of course thank you for listening
you can always contact us on that webby
thing or show at embedded fm and now how
about a quote from Neil Gaiman I've
always felt that violence was the last
refuge of the incompetent and empty
threats the last sanctuary of the
terminal Ian app
embeded is an independently produced
radio show that focuses on the many
aspects of engineering it is a
production of logical elegance and
embedded software a consulting company
in California if there are
advertisements in the show we did not
put them there and do not receive money
from them at this time our sponsors are
logical elegance and listeners like you